# Calvin Freese - Full Stack Web Developer

(763)-843-9369 | <u>calvin.p.freese@gmail.com</u> | Minneapolis, Minnesota 55409 GitHub: <u>https://bit.ly/2VVRiGC</u> | Portfolio: <u>https://bit.ly/2VTnwCd</u> | LinkedIn: <u>https://bit.ly/37YNPhr</u>

### SUMMARY

Dedicated Full Stack Web Developer intent on providing thorough and creative solutions while using empathy, problem-solving, and leadership skills refined by years of working in the IT space supporting customers in retail, corporate, and distribution environments. Web development certificate achieved through University of Minnesota College of Continuing and Professional Studies, St. Paul, Minnesota. Aim to deliver responsive websites, catered to the functional requirements of the client without sacrificing design by using my skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Reactjs. Successfully constructed Sequelize data models and API routing for an adventure game group project. Eager to collaborate with others to cultivate innovative user experiences.

- Promoted three times in four years due to ability to grasp and guide others on newly implemented procedures and tools.
- Exercised leadership in group projects by guiding the team to meet completion deadlines.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Debugging - Active Directory - One Identity Active Roles - SailPoint IdentityIQ - HTML5 - CSS3 - Bootstrap - Ulkit - Bulma - JavaScript - jQuery - Ajax - Node - Git - GitHub - Heroku - MySQL - MySQL Workbench - Sequelize - JawsDB - MongoDB - Mongoose - VSCode - Handlebars - React - Windows 10 - Mac OS - AS400 - zOS - PuTTY - Command Line - Reflection - Word - Excel - PowerPoint - Outlook - Visio - SharePoint - MS Teams - Cisco Jabber - Cisco Webex - Zoom - Slack - Skype - Adobe Photoshop - Adobe Illustrator - Final Cut Pro Cherwell Trebuchet - CA Service Desk - BMC Remedy - Remote Work - RSA SecurID

### **PROJECTS**

Worldwide COVID-19 - <a href="https://afazeez82.github.io/worldwidecovid19-githubio.com/">https://afazeez82.github.io/worldwidecovid19-githubio.com/</a>

Delivers COVID-19 statistics, news articles, and visual data for a selected country by utilizing API calls with jQuery/Ajax

- Defined JavaScript functions to create list items from the user's search query. Searches were stored to local storage to not be lost on page refresh or revisit.
- Inserted global and country data from the API into visual charts using the Charts.js library.
- o Technologies used include: HTML/CSS, Ulkit, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, Local Storage, Git, Github

### Jasmine-RPG - https://team-jasmine-rpg.herokuapp.com/

Fantasy-themed game that allows users to create a character to send on adventures or to the fight pits.

- Connected Sequelize models to end user inputs for character creation.
- Setup API and HTML routing for each path to serve the end user the correct handlebars file with injected SQL database information.
- Delegated tasks to team members to refine and complete HTML formatting, CSS styling, and Github pull requests.
- Technologies used include: HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, Node, npm packages, MySQL, MySQL Workbench, Git, Github, Heroku

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## UNFI, Eden Prairie, Minnesota FEB 2016 - PRESENT

# Supervisor Access Provisioning, MAR 2020 - Present

- Successfully led the team to consistently resolve 90% of requests within a 5-day SLA period. Previous SLA period was 14 days.
- Managed Access Provisioning department, responsible for 95% of all company access requests.
- Collaborated with IAM, IT Service Management, and Project Managers to smoothly implement company-wide projects by completing UAT and Production access requests for hundreds of users at time.

# IT Business Delivery Analyst, JUL 2019 - MAR 2020

- Thoroughly recorded gaps and overlaps in legacy processes, resulting in cross-training initiative and 10% increase in daily completed ticket counts.
- Increased quality of tickets by performing weekly team audits and outlining standard ticket requirements.

# IT Specialist II, SEPT 2018 - JUL 2019

- Proficiently migrated team tasks to a dynamic Sharepoint list, generated by MS Flow via switch/case statements based on day.
- Meticulously downsized team-owned knowledge documents by 85%.

#### IT Specialist I, FEB 2016 - SEPT 2018

- Performed JCL overrides and dataset adjustments to resolve failed mainframe jobs to prevent business impact.
- Assertively escalated high-priority incidents which required accurate triaging and engagement of multiple teams during the graveyard shift.

### Geek Squad, Shakopee, Minnesota - Consultation Agent - JUL 2014 - FEB 2016

- o Interacted with clients and performed initial troubleshooting for various client devices.
- Aided in the restoration and repairs of client units which included hardware and software installations, data transfers, and virus removals.

## **EDUCATION**

# University of Minnesota School of Continuing and Professional Studies, St. Paul, Minnesota

Full Stack Flex Web Development Program

Certificate of Completion - DEC 2020

Accelerated part-time 24 week program that provides curriculum on full stack programming, and experience collaborating on teams to create front-end and back-end coding solutions. Projects are geared towards solving for user-oriented problems, requiring empathy and ingenuity, as well as skills with various coding languages.

### Art Institutes International Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minnesota

60 credits

Attended the Visual FX and Motion Graphics program for five quarters.